



Professional Summary

Creative problem-solver with a skill for developing elegant solutions in the least amount of time. Employment as a Programmer in a national or multinational Company to utilize profund programming skills to develop augmented, virtual and mixed-reality applications to support Company research in next-generation immersive training.



Competitive Programming Journey

Hackerrank: https://www.hackerrank.com/ /profile/mdsamaul843

Codeforces: https://codeforces.com/profile/mdsamaul843

Codechef: https://www.codechef.com/use rs/mdsamaul843



WORK EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2024 – DEC 2024 [us softower ltd]

Trainee Programmer [Internship]

Work under IsDB-BISEW IT

Scholarship program as a trainee on

Web Application Development with

Microsoft C# .NET

PROFESSIONAL COURSES

JUN 2024 – DEC 2024 Web application development using ASP.NET IsDB-BISEW IT Scholarship programme

Online Course

FEB 2023 – DEC 2023

complete web development course +

SCIC-Pro: Job Hunting Battlefield

programming-hero----Batch 07

Phitron-------Batch 03

MD. SAMAUL ISLAM

ASP.NET & C# Programmer

+880 1981 154 473 | mdsamaul843@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mdsamaul | https://github.com/mdsamaul

CORE SKILLS

- Microsoft Technologies: C#, ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET MVC, Web API, Angular
- Development Tools: Microsoft Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, MS SQL Server Management Studio
- Scripting Languages: React, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Ajax, Json, TypeScript, CSS3, Bootstrap, TailwindCss, daisyUI
- **❖ Markup Language:** HTML5
- Database: SQL Server, MongoDB
- Report: Crystal Report
- Microsoft Office: MS Office Application
 Operating System: Windows and Linux

PROJECT

Online Ride Share

Authentication & Authorization | Role Management | Ride Booking System | Real-Time Tracking | Payment System | Vehicle Management | Fare Calculation | Chat System | Profile Management | Admin Dashboard | Employee Management | Attendance & Payroll Management | Reporting & Analytics | Multi Data Submission | User-Friendly Interface Technology: ASP.NET CORE MVC (Backend) Angular (Frontend), MS SQL Server, jQuery, JavaScript, Ajax, Json, Html, CSS, Bootstrap Git-Lint-1: https://github.com/mdsamaul/Oline-Ride-Share-idb-project Git-Lint-2: https://github.com/mdsamaul/OnlineRideShare2.o

■ Master Details CRUD Operation (ASP.NET Core MVC & .NET MVC)

Real-Time Updates (ajax) | Inline Editing | Search and Filters | Pagination | Export Features (CSV, Excel, PDF) | Bulk Actions | Row Highlighting | Master-Detail Synchronization | Audit Trail | Advanced Validation | File Upload | User Role Management | Dynamic Charts | Multi-Language Support | Dark Mode | Drag and Drop Reordering | History View | Custom Styling

Technology: ASP.NET CORE MVC, MS SQL Server, jQuery, JavaScript, Ajax, Json, Html, CSS, Bootstrap

Git-Link: https://github.com/mdsamaul/crud

Ecommerce Project

Add Product | Add to Cart | Delete from Cart | Total Price Calculation | Chat System | Client-side validation | Server-side validation | Popup | Design | Notification | Database using Mongodb |

Technology: Html, Css, Bootstrap, , MongoDb, jQuery, Ajax, Json, Note.js , JavaScript, Socket.io, Express.js, Multer

Git-Link: https://github.com/mdsamaul/gift-box

Chat system (JavaScript & jQuery)

Dynamic web view with attractive design | Group Chat | Single Chat | Image/File Sharing | Real-time Messaging | User Authentication | Typing Indicator | Read Receipts | Message | Notifications | User Status

Academic Education

JUN 2017 – DEC 2021 Jessore Polytechnic Institute (JPI)

Course Status: Completed CGPA: 3.74 out of 4.00

WORK EXPERIENCE

MAY 2024 - DEC 2021

Bio-Xin Cosmeceuticals

Work under MandsIT (front end

developer)

QA Testing (Android Application)



REFERENCES

Umme Aimun Nesa

Training instructor (.Net)

IsDB-BISEW IT Scholarship Programme

Relation: Academic Phone: 01736580206

E-mail:aimunnesa2@gmail.com

Sayed Zahidul Hasan

Project Consultant

Show & Tell Consulting Ltd.

IsDB-BISEW IT Scholarship Programme

Relation: Academic Phone: +8801817015015

Email:zahid@showtellconsulting.com

Md. Shazedul

Center manager US Software Ltd. Relation: Academic

Phone: +88 01912-347650

Email:shazedul02071987@gmail.com

Technology: Html, CSS, Bootstrap, javaScript, express.js, multer, jQuery, Ajax, Json, Notify.js

Git-Link: https://github.com/mdsamaul/we-Chat

Metro Passenger (Visual Studio C# Console)

Object Approach | Generic Approach | Interface | Abstraction | Methods | And – Update – Read – Delete metro passenger

Technology: Visual Studio C# Console

Git-Link: https://github.com/mdsamaul/metro-project

♣ Brandly Ecommerce (React)

Ecommerce Web application Included there many brand there site **Using-dependency**: @smastrom/react-rating | firebase | hamburger-react | localforage | match-sorter | pure-react-carousel | query-string | react | react-content-zoom | react-dom | react-icons | react-image-gallery | react-img-zoom | react-inner-image-zoom | react-rating | react-responsive-carousel | react-router-dom | react-scroll-parallax | react-slick | react-tabs | slick-carousel | sort-by | swiper

Technology: Html, CSS, JavaScript, React, Vite.js, env, express.js TailwindCss, DaisyUi.

Git-Link: https://github.com/mdsamaul/new-brandlly

OTHERS CURRICULAM

- Web application Development using Microsoft ASP.NET under IsDB-BISEW IT Scholarship program.
- ✓ Complete Web Development Course With Jhankar Mahbub, online course (Dec 2022 June 2023) + SCIC
- ✓ Phitron.io (CS Fundamentals With Phitron, online course)
- Problem solving skills on URI Hackerrank, Codeforces, Codechef Online Judge.
- ✓ More than 2+ year experience in programming related field.
- Real time project experience in trainee time.
- Lead and manage all students of our class as a class representative
- √ 100+ problem solved on URI online programming contest platform
- An active member of our programming club in Southeast University

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name: Md. Samaul Islam

Permanent Address: Sundarpur, Maheshpur, Jhenaidah.

Present Address : Agargaon, Shere Bangla Nagar, Dhaka-1207

❖ Date of Birth : 15/11/2000

Religion : Islam ~~~ Blood Group : B+

Marital Status : Unmarried ~~~ Nationality : Bangladeshi

STRENGTH

- Well organized and Capable to work under pressure.
- P Quick learner, Ready to adapt to new technologies.
- Good interpersonal and communication skills.
- 1 Interested in knowing new Technologies and Nature.

DECLARATION

As a security clearance I have no criminal records in any civil court or in any police station. I do here by declare that the particulars provided here are true and no miss information given.

Sianature